haptik.co 2017-08-26

# Haptik - We Get It Done

### A. GENERAL

1.1 Haptik is committed to the protection of personal information provided by the users to us. You agree that your use of Haptik’s mobile application, website and WAPsite(the "Application"), owned by Haptik Infotech Private Limited (“Haptik”), implies your consent to the collection and use of your personal information (or your children's personal information) in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

1.2 We at Haptik take the privacy of its users seriously. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our users while providing a personalised and valuable service.

### B. PERSONAL INFORMATION

2.1 This Privacy Policy is published in compliance of:   
(i) Section 43A of the Information Technology Act, 2000; and    
(ii) Regulation 4 of the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Information) Rules, 2011 (the “SPI Rules”) 

2.2 “Personal Information” is defined under the SPI Rules to mean any information that relates to a natural person, which, either directly or indirectly, in combination with other information available or likely to be available with a body corporate, is capable of identifying such person.

2.3 The SPI Rules further define “sensitive personal data or information” of a person to mean Personal Information about that person relating to:   
(i) passwords;    
(ii) financial information such as bank accounts, credit and debit card details or other payment instrument details;   
(iii) physical, physiological and mental health condition;    
(iv) name, age, address, e-mail, phone number, date of birth, sexual orientation;   
(v) medical records and history;   
(vi) biometric information;   
(vii) information received by body corporate under lawful contract or otherwise;  
(viii) visitor details as provided at the time of registration or thereafter; and   
(ix) call data records. 

All the aforementioned information is collectively referred to as “Personal Information.” 

###  C. INFORMATION COLLECTED 

3.1 We collect Personal Information from you at registration and other times (for instance, when you download the Application) such as your name, your picture, email address, postal address, mobile phone number, a list of all apps on your phone, your SMS, among other things.

3.2 You are under no obligation to provide us with such information. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, you may not be able to use the Application and we may not be able to respond effectively to your query or provide you with certain services.

### D. DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

4.1 When a user uses the Application, Haptik may collect users’ mobile phone number, mailing address, email ID, Pin Code, other apps on users’ phones, login information for Facebook, Twitter and Google account and other Personal Information such as service Account Numbers. A high standard of security is maintained by Haptik for its users; however the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. So, whilst we will do our best to protect user information, particularly with respect to protection of personal data, we cannot ensure the security of user data transmitted to us via the internet or any other medium.

### E. COOKIES 

5.1 To improve the responsiveness for our users, we may use "cookies", or similar electronic tools to collect information to assign each visitor a unique, random number as a User Identification (User ID) to understand the user's individual interests using the identified computer. Unless you voluntarily identify yourself (through registration, for example), we will have no way of knowing who you are, even if we assign a cookie to your computer. The only Personal Information a cookie can contain is information you supply. A cookie cannot read data off your hard drive. Our advertisers may also assign their own cookies to your browser (if you click on their ads), a process that we do not control. 

### F. INFORMATION SHARING 

6.1 Haptik may share the sensitive Personal Information to any third party/ service provider/Alliance Partner without obtaining the prior consent of the user in the following limited circumstances:   
(a) When it is requested or required by law or by any court or governmental agency or authority to disclose, for the purpose of verification of identity, or for the prevention, detection, investigation including cyber incidents, or for prosecution and punishment of offences. These disclosures are made in good faith and belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary for enforcing these Terms; for complying with the applicable laws and regulations.   
(b) Haptik proposes to share such information within its group companies and officers and employees of such group companies for the purpose of processing Personal Information on its behalf. We also ensure that these recipients of such information agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.   
(c) Haptik may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when the user visits the Application. These companies may use Personal Information about the user’s visit to the Application and other Applications in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to the user.   
(d) Haptik shall transfer information about the user in case Haptik is acquired by or merged with another company.

6.2 Once the user permits, we may obtain additional information such as transactional information available on your device, to personalise your experience and improve the Application suggestions. This data may be shared within Times Internet Limited (“TIL”) portals/applications including TIL ad network ‘Colombia’. Please be informed that the data collection is handled securely, including transmitting it using modern cryptography (secure HTTPS connection). Please note that the transactional information shall neither be stored nor be shared with any third party and shall be purely utilized for enhancing the user experience and personalising the services within TIL networks. 

### G. YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS POLICY

7.1 By using this Application, you consent to the collection and use of your information by Haptik and to this Privacy Policy. If we change the Privacy Policy then we will post these changes on this page.

7.2 Whilst we use all reasonable endeavours to protect your security in the manner described above, we consider that it is only appropriate to advise users that data transmission over the internet, the world wide web or any other type of network cannot always be guaranteed as 100% secure and therefore that you use the Application at your own risk.

### H. YOUR RIGHTS

8.1 You have a legal right to a copy of any personal information about you held by us. You also have a right to correct any errors in that information. As mentioned above, you have a right to request that we cease to use your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

###  I. ACCESSING AND UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION 

9.1 When you use Haptik's Applications, we make good faith efforts to provide you, as and when requested by you, with access to your personal information and shall further ensure that any Personal Information or sensitive personal data or information found to be inaccurate or deficient shall be corrected or amended as feasible, subject to any requirement for such personal information or sensitive personal data or information to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Because of the way we maintain certain services, after you delete your information, residual copies may take a period of time before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems. 

9.2 We may disclose to third party services certain personally identifiable information listed below:  

  * Information you provide us such as name, email, mobile phone number
  * Information we collect as you access and use our service, including contacts in your device, application packages present on your device, email a 

This information is shared with third party service providers so that we can:  

  * Personalize the app for you
  * Perform behavioral analytics
  * Provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you

###  J. INFORMATION SECURITY 

10.1 We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, including appropriate encryption and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. 

10.2 All information gathered on Haptik is securely stored within the Haptik controlled database. The database is stored on servers secured behind a firewall; access to the servers is password-protected and is strictly limited. However, as effective as our security measures are, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. And, of course, any information you include in a posting to the discussion areas is available to anyone with Internet access. 

10.3 However the internet is an ever evolving medium. We may change our privacy policy from time to time to incorporate necessary future changes. Of course, our use of any information we gather will always be consistent with the policy under which the information was collected, regardless of what the new policy may be. 

10.4 We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Any complaints or concerns with regards to content or to report any abuse of laws or breach of these terms may be taken up with the designated grievance officer as mentioned below via post or by sending an email to hello@haptik.co to Mr. Aakrit Vaish (Grievance Officer). 

###  K. GRIEVANCE REDRESSAL 

11.1 Redressal Mechanism: Any complaints, abuse or concerns with regards to content and or comment or breach of these terms shall be immediately informed to the designated Grievance Officer as mentioned below via in writing or through email signed with the electronic signature to .   
Mr. Aakrit Vaish (Grievance Officer).   
Haptik Infotech Private Limited   
Email: hello@haptik.co   
Address: 8th Floor, Cello Triumph, IB Patel Rd, Goregaon East, Mumbai, Maharashtra 400063   
Ph: +912226854067   
We request you to please provide the following information in your complaint:-   
(a) A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the copyright owner for the purposes of the complaint.    
(b) Identification of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed.    
(c) Identification of the material on our Application that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity.    
(d) The address, telephone number or e-mail address of the complaining party.    
(e) A statement that the complaining party has a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent or the law.
